TV를 볼 때에는 방을 밝게 하고 TV에서 떨어져서 봅시다.
When you're watching television, be sure to keep your room bright and keep distance from the TV!
강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
참 재수 없어요! 이런 폭풍치는 밤에 고작 얘들 장난감을 옮겨야 하다니.
What the heck. Why are we moving children's toys in a stormy night?
고작 얘들 장난감? 무슨 소릴. 우리가 옮기고 있는 건 악마다.
Children's toys, eh? You have no idea, do you? We're moving a devil.
아, 악마?
D- devil?
어이, 앞을 봐!
Eyes on the road!
아, 네.
Ah, right.
무서운 악마지. 적이라고 판단된 것이라면 그게 뭐든지 무슨 일이 있어도 파괴하는 붉은 악마야.
It's a frightening devil. The red devil that will destroy whatever it identifies as an enemy, no matter what.
DVL형 블로소메일
DVL Type Blossomail
폭주! 붉은 악마
Rage! Red Devil
(en: Redrun Away)
뭐야, 이 데스 메다로트는?
What is this Death Medarot?
본 사가 곧 판매하려 하는 개발중인 최강의 데스 메다로트 시리즈 1대, 블로소메일입니다.
It's the first product in development in the lineup of strongest Death Medarots: Blossomail. It is almost ready for market.
블로소메일?
Blossomail?
프로토타입이지만 시험 중에 전자파에 과도하게 노출되어 컴퓨터에 오류가 발생해서
While it's a prototype, during the last trial, it was overly exposed to electromagnetic waves and began to malfunction.
보시는 대로 저희 명령을 듣지 않고 폭주하게 되었습니다.
As you see, it stopped responding to our orders and began to rage.
그 때는 강제로 봉인해서 별 일 없이 넘겼습니다만,
Back then, we were able to forcefully seal it and no accident happened,
어젯밤 본사로 운송하던 도중 수송 트럭에 교통 사고가 일어나서 강제 봉인이 풀려 블로소메일이 사라져 버렸습니다.
but yesterday, due to a road accident, the seal was broken and now Blossomail is nowhere to be found.
블로소메일은 자신에게 피해를 주거나 직접 적이라고 판단한 것은 막대한 공격으로 철저히 파괴하는 최강의 데스 메다로트입니다.
Blossomail is the strongest Death Medarot that will definitely destroy everything that's considered harmful.
이대로라면 사회에 대혼란을 불러일으킬 가능성이 있습니다.
It might bring a big chaos to society.
코쿠류 도련님, 꼭 당신의 힘으로 포획해 주시길 바랍니다.
Master Kokuryu, we'd like to ask you to capture it with your abilities.
블로소메일이라. 좋아, 맡겨 둬.
Blossomail, eh? Alright, leave it to me.
어이, 뭐야!
Hey, what's up!?
뭐야? 꽤 소란스럽네.
What's going on? It's pretty noisy here.
사고라도 났나?
Maybe an accident?
-뭔 방해야!
-어서 치워!
-What's that?
-Someone get rid of it!
뭐야, 저 메다로트?
What's up with that Medarot?
처음 보네.
Never saw that before.
언제까지 거기 박혀 있을 거야? 안 움직이면 날려버린다?
Aren't you going to move or what? I'm gonna drive through you if you don't move!
장난감이든 뭐든 어쩔 수 없나.
It's a toy, after all.
무, 무슨 힘이야!
H- how strong!
저, 저건 메다로트가 아니야. 전혀 다른...
T- that's not a Medarot. It's more different...
-메타비! 얘들이-
-알아!
-Metabee! The children!
-Got it!
야, 괴물! 너 뭐냐!
Hey, monster! What are you!?
적으로서의 가치 없음.
Target unworthy as an enemy.
이 틈에 어서 차 돌려요!
Take the chance ot run away!
아, 알았어!
G- got it!
뭐, 뭐야, 너 뭐야?
W- wha- what are you?
메타비!
Metabee!
나 열받았다!
You're making me angry!
레클리스 모드야, 메타비!
To Reckless Mode, Metabee!
각오해라!
You'd better be prepared!
이, 이게! 가! 가! 이게!
Y- you! Move! Get lost! You!
어라?
Huh?
누굴 바보로 아나!
Are you making fun of me!?
뭐, 뭐야!?
W- what!?
마, 마치 아기 다루는 것 같아. 수준이 너무 다르잖아!
I- it's treating Metabee like a baby! Its level is completely different!
젠장...
Damn...
메, 메타비! 일어나!
M- Metabee! Wake up!
잇키, 어서 타.
Ikki, get on.
돌연 도부로쿠 마을에 나타난 수수께끼의 메다로트가 마을을 계속 파괴해 나가고 있습...
A mysterious Medarot, suddenly appeared in Doburoku village, is keeping to destroy the village...
먼저 모습을 드러내 주다니. 가자, 긴카이.
It showed up first; isn't that great? Let's go, Ginkai.
좋아!
Alright!
정말, 뭐야, 그 놈은!
Really, what the heck was that bastard!?
아마 데스 메다로트 사의 최신 모델일 거야.
It must be the newest model from Death Medarot company.
-뭐라고!?
-What!?
잠깐, 메타비, 움직이지 마. 못 고치잖아.
Hey, Metabee, don't move. I can't repair you.
아, 미안.
Er, sorry.
잇키! 뉴스 봤어?
Ikki! Did you see the news?
어, 아리카. 뭔 일이야?
Oh, Arika, what's up?
빨간 동체를 가진 메다로트가 도부로쿠 마을에서 날뛰고 있대!
A Medarot with a red body is raging in Doburoku village!
걔 덕분에 메타비도 이렇게 됐고...
Thanks to that guy, Metabee's, well, as you see.
메타비 씨, 괜찮아? 그 붉은 거에 당했어?
Mr. Metabee, are you alright? Did that red thing get you?
당한 거 아니야! 내가 잠깐 방심했을 뿐이야! 다음에 보면 절대 안 져!
It didn't get me! I was just unprepared! I won't lose next time if I ever meet it again!
-그건 힘들어.
-어?
-You probably can't.
-What?
그건 그냥 데스 메다로트가 아니야. 붉은 악마지.
Thatis not simply a Death Medarot. It's a red devil.
붉은 악마?
Red devil?
데스 메다로트 사가 다음에 발매하고자 하는 힘만을 중시해 만든 무서운 기계.
It's a frightening machine that Death Medarot company was developing, only with power in mind.
저런 게 대량으로 출하돼 아이들이 쓰게 되면 최악이야.
If that ever gets released to public and kids start using it, then it's the worst.
최악? 뭔 소리야, 나에 씨.
The worst? Please explain more, Ms. Nae.
메다로트 사의 정신인 메다로터와 메다로트의 우정과 신뢰가 없어지고 살벌한 전투만의 세계가 될 거라 생각해.
The spirit of Medarot Company - the friendship and trust between Medarotter and Medarot - will disappear,
and the only remaining in the world will be brutal battles.
지금까지의 메다로트를 버리고 더욱 강한 데스 메다로트로 규칙 없는 로보틀을 반복하게 될 뿐이라니... 싫어.
People will abandon Medarots they got, and repeat Robattles without rules using stronger Death Medarots...
That sounds bad.
그러니까 이 몸이 그 붉은 악마를 지금 쳐부술 거야!
That's why I am going to destroy that red devil right away!
힘들댔지? 지금 메타비의 힘으로는 승산이 없어.
Again, bad idea. You are not likely to win with your current powers.
그런...
No way...
그래도 나에 씨! 이대로 붉은 악마를 그대로 두면 이 마을은 큰 혼란에 빠질 거야!
But, Ms. Nae! If we leave the red devil like this, the village will fall into a big chaos!
뭐, 메타비가 그라피티 모드로 변형할 수 있다면야...
Well, if Metabee can transform into Graffiti Mode...
그라피티 모드?
Graffiti Mode?
특별한 메다로트만 가지고 있는 최종 변형 말이야.
It's the ultimate transformation of a limited choices of Medarots.
레클리스 모드 이외로도 변형 가능한 거야?
Can I transform into something else than Reckless Mode?
응. 너도 가능할 거야.
Yes. You should be able to do that, too.
-잇키! 그라피티 모드로 변형이야!
-좋아!
-Ikki! Let me transform into Graffiti Mode!
-Alright!
잠깐만. 아직 수리는 안 끝났어. 완료될 때까지 얌전히 있어.
Wait. Repair isn't over yet. Keep still until it's done.
네...
Okay...
적으로서의 가치 없음.
Target unworthy as an enemy.
유니트리스! 라이플, 개틀링으로 일제 사격해!
Unitrix! Fusillade using your rifle and Gatling!
뭐야!?
What!?
긴카이, 레클리스 모드로 연계 공격해.
Ginkai, use Reckless Mode to do linked attack.
어!
Right!
-레클리스 모드!
-Reckless Mode!
노멀 모드인데도 굉장히 빠르구나.
It's really fast even in normal mode.
유니트리스!
Unitrix!
뭐야, 코쿠류!
What is it, Kokuryu!?
도저히 쓰러트릴 수 있는 상대가 아니야. 좀 더 알아보고 다시 해 보자. 돌아가자, 엑스사이즈.
It's not an enemy that we can easily take down. Let's try again after further inspection. Let's go back, Excise.
나는 안 달아나! 내겐 비장의 수가 있어! 유니트리스, 그라피티 모드야!
I won't run away! I have a trump card! Unitrix, to Graffiti Mode!
유니트리스, 네 진짜 힘을 보여줘!
Unitrix, show it your true powers!
좋아! 메달을 쏘아! 단숨에 기능 정지시켜!
Alright! Shoot its medal! Make it stop functioning at once!
흥, 해냈다.
Hmph, we did it.
괴, 괴물이다!
M- monster!
Medarot Damashii - Subtitles by Subdiver
달아나, 유니트리스!
Run, Unitrix!
키스터틀, 난 두목한테 알릴 테니까 넌 놈들을 쫒아!
Kiethturtle, I'll let the boss know, while you go chase them!
알겠습니다!
Understood!
무기 어깨 무겁지 않아, 메타비?
Isn't weapon shoulder too heavy for you, Metabee?
무슨, 별 거 아니야!
Nah, it's nothing!
잇키, 준비 됐어.
Ikki, I'm ready.
좋아!
Great!
메타비! 그라피티 모드야!
Metabee! To Graffiti Mode!
오, 멋져!
How cool!
왠지 완전 잘 될 거 같은데?
I think I'm good to go!
아리카, 몇 초 걸렸어?
Arika, how long did it take?
7초 반.
7.5 seconds.
늦어. 시간이 너무 오래 걸려.
Too long. He's taking too much time.
뭐, 처음이니까 이 정도...
Well, it's his first attempt, so...
7초 반동안 그 붉은 악마가 덤벼들면 틀림없이 고철이 될 거야.
If that red devil decides to attack you during that 7.5 seconds, you'll end up becoming a scrap metal.
뭘 낙담하는 거야? 연습해서 변신 시간을 줄이면 되잖아!
Why are you feeling down? Practice and lessen the time taken to transform!
알았어! 네 말이 맞아!
Yes! You're right!
메타비, 계속 연습하자!
Metabee, let's practice!
어, 어!
Er, yeah!
아리카, 시간 재 줘!
Arika, please measure the time!
맡겨 둬.
Sure, I will!
그라피티 모드!
Graffiti Mode!
뭐, 어쨌든, 빨개요.
Well, anyway, it's red.
-그래?
-엄청 빨라요!
-Is that so?
-It's super fast!
-그래서 어디야?
-두목! 거의 다 왔어요!
-So, where is it?
-Boss! We're almost there!
알지, 니들! 그 미친 붉은 메다로트를 쓰러트리면 우리는 스타야! 전력으로 하자!
You know what to do, guys! Take that crazy red Medarot down and we're stars! Do your best!
네!
Right!
미친 붉은 메다로트? 설마...
Crazy red Medarot? Could it be...
아, 그런 거였구나.
Oh, I see.
여보세요?
Hello?
-코쿠류! 나야!
-어, 긴카이야? 뭔 일이야?
-Kokuryu! It's me!
-Oh, it's you, Ginkai. What's up?
사, 살려줘! 블로소메일이 우릴 쫒고 있어!
H- help me! Blossomail is chasing us!
안됐네. 나 지금 바빠.
Too bad. I'm busy at the moment.
제, 제발! 그런 소리 말고 도와주러 와 줘!
P- please! Don't say that and come help me!
블로소메일은 적이라고 판단한 이상 파괴될 때까지 공격을 멈추지 않아.
Blossomail will not stop attacking once it identified as an enemy until it gets destroyed.
-뭐, 뭐라고!?
-내가 뭐라고 해서 어떻게 될 문제가 아니야. 그럼.
-W- what!?
-It's not something I can deal with. See ya.
유니트리스!
Unitrix!
유니트리스...
Unitrix...
자, 가자.
Let's go.
딱 4초.
Exact 4 seconds.
꽤 빨라지긴 했는데도, 아직 갈 길이 머네.
You did become faster, but you still have a lot to work on.
다시 한번!
Again!
살려줘!
Help me!
긴카이!
Ginkai!
블로소메일이 유니트릭스를 죽이러 와.
Blossomail is coming to kill Unitrix.
너무 네 편한 대로 구는 거 아냐? 항상 우릴 눈엣가시로 여기는 주제에.
Aren't you being selfish? You treat us like an eyesore all the time.
뭔 일이야. 블로소메일이 뭐야?
What's going on? What is Blossomail?
데스 메다로트 사의 최강 데스 메다로트. 아니, 붉은 악마야!
It's the strongest Death Medarot of Death Medarot Company. No, it's a red devil!
그 놈이구나.
That guy.
블로소메일은 한번 적이라고 판단하면 파괴할 때까지 공격을 멈추지 않아!
Once identified something as an enemy, Blossomail does not stop attacking until it's destroyed!
역시 데스 메다로트 사가 만들 만한 데스 메다로트구나.
That sounds like a Death Medarot which only Death Medarot Company would make.
에, 그리고 컴퓨터에 오류가 나서 사람이 말하는 걸 안 들어! 제발 도와줘!
Er, and its computer is malfunctioning and isn't listening to what humans say! Please help me!
설마 짜증나는 놈이라고 해도, 자기 메다로트를 지키기 위해 이렇게나 열심히 숙이고 있어!
I do hate him, but he is lowering his head in front of us to protect his Medarot!
이래선 도와줄 수밖에 없지.
We will have to help.
그래.
Yes.
잠깐!
Stop!
이라 해봤자 멈출 얘들이 아니지.
...well, I saw that coming.
적으로서의 가치 없음.
Target unworthy as an enemy.
두목, 넘 조용해요!
Boss, it's too silent here!
왜, 왠지 기분 나쁜 분위기...
I- I don't like the atmosphere here...
벌벌 떨지 마라! 우린 메다로트가 3대나 있어! 저긴...
Don't be frightened! We have 3 Medarots! The other side...
나왔다!
It's there!
너는...!
You...!
그래, 너희들도 왔구나.
I thought you would come.
블로소메일은?
Where's Blossomail?
저 안에다. 지금 스크류즈 놈들하고 싸우고 있다.
It's in there, fighting against Screws guys.
키쿠히메 얘들?
Kikuhime?
너, 너무해!
H- how terrible!
키쿠히메!
Kikuhime!
-쟤 악마야! 페퍼캣!
-블루즈독...
-That's a devil! Peppercat!
-Bluesdog...
블로소메일은?
Where's Blossomail?
저기!
Over there!
2층이구나. 가자.
2nd floor? Let's go.
블로소메일 놈! 어디야!
Blossomail! Where are you!?
나누어서 찾아 보자.
Let's divide.
그, 그만해!
S- stop it!
이자식!
You bastard!
누굴 바보로 알고!
How dare you treat me like that!
메타비! 그라피티 모드야!
Metabee! To Graffiti Mode!
좋아!
Alright!
메타비!
Metabee!
이번에는 내가 상대한다.
I will face you this time.
그라피티 모드.
Graffiti Mode.
적. 도쿠스를 쓰러트려라.
Enemy. Take down Dorcus.
나, 날아?
H- he's flying!
반중력 발생 장치다.
He has an antigravity generator.
어디 숨었나...
Where did you hide in?
도쿠스. 전방을 조심해라!
Dorcus! Watch your front!
도쿠스!
Dorcus!
그라피티 모드로도 못 이기는가...
Even Graffiti Mode didn't work...
좋아.
Alright.
잇키.
Ikki.
다시 메타비를 그라피티 모드로 변형해 주지 않겠나.
Wouldn't you like to transform Metabee into Graffiti Mode again?
그래.
Right.
그라피티 모드야, 메타비!
To Graffiti Mode, Metabee!
좋아!
Alright!
도쿠스, 블로소메일의 등으로 돌아 들어가서 움직임을 멈춰라.
Dorcus, go round and cut into Blossomail's back and make it stop.
잇키. 등의 메다스플레이어를 박아 넣어.
Ikki. Hammer in Medasplayer on his back.
-어?
-그러면 도쿠스도 부서질 거야!
-What?
-Then Dorcus will be destroyed, too!
상관 없다. 쏘아라.
It doesn't matter. Fire.
쏴, 잇키.
Fire, Ikki.
어째, 잇키.
What should I do, Ikki?
쏴, 잇키.
Fire, Ikki.
나에 씨!
Ms. Nae!
그 외에 쓰러트릴 방법은 없어. 도쿠스 수리는 내가 책임을 질 테니까 쏴.
That's the only way to take it down. I'll repair Dorcus if I have to, so feel free to fire.
메타비! 메다스플레이어 준비!
Metabee! Prepare your Medasplayer!
알았어.
Got it.
발사!
Fire!
됐나?
Did it work?
도쿠스!
Dorcus!
대단한 위력이야!
What power!
저 자식!
That bastard!
메타비!
Metabee!
메다스플레이어도 안 먹히다니.
Even Medasplayer didn't work...
얘는 어떻게 해도 못 이기는 거야?
Can I ever defeat this guy?
포기하면 안 돼!
Don't give up!
레클리스 모드로 변형해, 메타비!
Transform into Reckless Mode, Metabee!
-뭐라고!?
-내게 좋은 생각이 있어! 어서!
-What!?
-I have an idea! Hurry!
그대로 바로 핀으로 달려!
Run to the pins right now!
멈춰, 메타비!
Stop, Metabee!
해냈어, 메타비!
We did it, Metabee!
했어했어!
We did it, we did it!
해냈어, 해냈어!
Yes, we did! We sure did!
무서운 놈이었어!
That was a scary guy!
뭐, 그럴지도?
Well, I guess!
아직도 안 쓰러졌어!
It's still alive!
적. 메타비를 쓰러트려라.
Enemy. Take down Metabee.
무서워!
I'm scared!
변형했어!
It transformed!
3, 2, 1, 0.
멈췄어.
It stopped.
디 엔드.
The End.
코쿠류!
Kokuryu!
이거 어떻게 된 거야!?
What happened!?
알아보니까 블로소메일은 시험 중이어서 24시간 후에 멈추도록 설정되어 있었어.
According to my research, Blossomail was going through an experiment and is supposed to stop working after 24 hours.
뭐, 뭐야! 그런 거라면 그런 거라고 말해 주면 좋았을 걸!
O- oh, is that so? You could have told us that!
블로소메일의 힘이 어느 정도인지 알아보고 싶어서 감히 자유롭게 날뛰게 냅뒀었어.
I wanted to find out the strength of Blossomail, so I let it rage as much as it wanted.
-이자식!
-코쿠류! 우릴 실험 재료로 썼다는 거야?!
-You bastard!
-Kokuryu! How dare you use us as test subjects?!
뭐하는 놈이야?!
What kind of guy is that?!
수고했어. 실험은 끝났으니까 블로소메일은 회수할게.
Good job. Now that the experiment is over, I'll take back Blossomail.
회수해도 돼.
You can withdraw it now.
실례합니다.
Excuse us.
텐료 잇키, 실험 중이었던 걸 행운으로 알아. 그럼.
Tenryo Ikki, consider it lucky that it was in an experiment. See you.
-별 일은 없습니다.
-좋아, 옮겨.
-네.
-Nothing serious.
-Alright, then move.
-Got it.
같이 가, 코쿠류!
Wait for me, Kokuryu!
흥! 어디 한번 다시 와 봐라! 언제라도 복수해 주겠어!
Hmph! Come back whenever you want! You will be paid!
흥이다!
Meh!
물러.
Aren't you naive.
만약 저 블로소메일이 완전히 코쿠류 손에서 명령대로 움직이게 된다면 무서운 상대가 될 거야.
If that Blossomail ever gets complete and follows Kokuryu's orders, then it will become a frightening enemy.
그렇다. 데스 메다로트 사를 쉽게 보지 않는 게 좋다.
She's right. You'd better not look down of Death Medarot Company.
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
숲 속에서 화려하게 핀 수많은 꽃.
Flowers are blooming in a forest.
여기는 아리카가 정성을 담아 꾸민 비밀의 꽃밭.
This secret flower garden is raised by Arika with a lot of efforts.
그걸 모르는 수수께끼의 메다로터는 요란한 로보틀로 꽃밭을 엉망으로 만들고 만다.
Not knowing that, the Mysterious Medarotter makes a mess out of the flower garden by a loud Robattle.
깊히 상처입은 아리카. 그런 대로 막 복구하던 꽃밭에서 이번엔 도쿠스와 메타비의 로보틀이 시작되고 만다.
Arika's feelings are deeply hurt. When they were recovering the flower garden, Dorcus and Metabee's Robattle begins.
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 아리카의 꽃밭
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Arika's Flower Garden
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!